SOFTWARE ENGINEER, DBA

Career Overview

Successful SQL Administrator/Developer with experience in building complex scripts, queries, reports, and applications. Over 16 years of IT professional experience with expertise in software development, relational database design, quality assurance testing, and technical project management. Experience working with Microsoft SQL Server databases - monitoring, tuning, backup / recovery, user management. Experience with SQL database development including queries, stored procedures, and applications integrated with SQL. Experience in System Integration, Data Migration, ETL (Extract-Transform-Load), Data Mapping, Data Cleanup. Software development experience using various programming languages, including C/C++, C#, ASP, .NET, and T-SQL. Working knowledge of all aspects of SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle). Experience with client interactions, team meetings and discussions, product requirements gathering, and translating functional requirements into quality assurance test scripts. Knowledge and experience installing, configuring and maintaining MS SQL Server Administration,, working as a 24x7 on-call support for high availability production systems. Excellent analytical, troubleshooting, communication and interpersonal skills. Oualifications

- Programming Languages: T-SQL, VBScript, C, C++, C#, .NET, HTML, Java, ASP, TCL/TK
- Tools & Libraries: MS Visual Studio .NET 2008/2010/2012, DAO, ODBC, Surround SCM, SoftwareKey Licensing
- RDBMS, ETL& Data: MS SQL Server 2000/2005/2008/2012, SSRS, SSIS, SSAS, DTS, MS Access, CVS, XML
- Hardware & Networking: IBM PC Compatibles/Windows, TCP/IP, FTP, HTTP, Telnet, Symantec Backup Exec
- Office Software: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Presentations, Projects, OpenOffice, Internet Explorer, Google Chrome
- Financial Processing: NCR, Diebold, Visa II, ISO 8583

Work Experience

Software Engineer, DBA

January 2012 to Current Isys Technologies il/4 Dulles, VA

- Maintain all SQL environments for the company, from production application DBs, to test and development DBs, to operations DBs.
- Monitor database backups and SQL jobs.
- Deploy SQL database application updates through the application deployment process ensuring the same updates get deployed to multiple client databases.
- Ensure application database schemas remain consistent between clients.
- Design and document database enhancements to products.
- Technology lead for project with over 100 clients.
- Project includes gathering, importing, cleaning, and migrating data for production use.
- This is a highly complex project with many variables for each client.
- Troubleshoot and resolve production database issues.
- Design and create SQL Reporting Services reports for various products and clients.
- Design and implement SQL Analysis Services data warehouse for client statistics.

Systems Engineer

January 2000 to January 2012 FutureSoft, Inc it/4 City, STATE

- Provide 24x7 customer support for time critical applications, databases, and utilities provided by the company.
- Communicate with customers, vendors, strategic partners, development staff, and sales staff to gather requirements, review specifications, and create project plans.
- Develop custom utilities and scripts for card management, debit card pin calculation, transaction simulation, and file transformation.
- Customize and deliver software to customers on location internationally and remotely.
- Designed and implemented a customer trouble report tracking system, migrated data from MS Access, MySQL, and MS SQL.
- Designed and coded web-based user interface to a transaction processing system.
- Developed multiple switch interfaces using message formats like ISO 8583.
- Responsible for all testing, installing, migrating, upgrading all customers including International.
- Created various customer and technical documents for the company software.
- Created an internal web interface using .NET for time tracking, stored the data in a database, and created custom SQL reports for various departments.

IT Administrator Co-op

January 1998 to January 1999 The University Of Akron Continuing Education il/4 City, STATE

- Maintained computer labs with software and hardware.
- Maintained student information and registration.
- Created and produced reports from the registration system.
- Provided computer support for the Continuing Education department.

Education and Training

 $Masters\ of\ Science: Management\ Information\ Technology\ Management\ ,\ 2004\ Colorado\ Technical\ University\ i^1\!/\!_4\ City\ ,\ State\ Management\ Information\ Technology\ Management\ }$

Bachelors of Science : Computer Science , 1999 The University of Akron i1/4 City , State Computer Science CERTIFICATES Networking and Telecommunications , Systems Analysis and Integration, Project Management Interests

Family, role playing and board games, and computer technologies. Skills

.NET, ASP, Backup Exec, C, C++, Hardware, client, clients, customer support, CVS, DAO, DTS, data warehouse, databases, database, debit, ETL, XML, Financial, FTP, HTML, HTTP, Internet Explorer, ISO, computer support, Java, MS Access, C#, Excel, Office, Outlook, PowerPoint, Windows, 2000, Microsoft Word, MySQL, Networking, Networking and Telecommunications, ODBC, IBM PC Compatibles, Presentations, Programming, Project Management, project plans, RDBMS, Reporting, sales, scripts, simulation, MS SQL Server, MS SQL, SQL, statistics, strategic, switch, Symantec, Systems Analysis and Integration, TCL/TK, TCP/IP, Telnet, T-SQL, transaction processing, Troubleshoot, upgrading, user interface, utilities, VBScript, MS Visual Studio Additional Information

• INTERESTS Family, role playing and board games, and computer technologies.